對不起。
Sorry.
你夏天要幹什麼？
What are you doing over the summer?
我在加油站找了份工作
I have a job pumping gas.
你終於讓最高法院聽你的了，嗯？
You finally got the Supreme Court to hear your case, huh?
你呢？
What about you?
不知道。
I don't know.
你覺得在這更好？
You thought it'd be nicer over here?
嗯
Yeah.
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
找點什麼送我媽媽生日禮物
I'm looking for something for my mom's birthday.
你的意思是說，萬一有人偶爾在沙灘上丟了
You mean, in case somebody happened to leave...
一個Cuisinart（美國廚具品牌）的東西或者一個鑽石戒指？
a Cuisinart or a diamond ring lying on the beach?
是啊，那就行。必須得是你做的，或者是你找到的東西。
Yeah, that would qualify. It has to be omething either you make or find.
- 她生日是什麼時候？
- 下周。
- When's her birthday?
- Next week.
真美。
That's beautiful.
給你媽媽的。
It's for your mother.
你送給她。
You give it to her.
好
Okay.
在那一定更好。
It must be nicer over there.
過來，切這些。
Here, chop these.
不對，不對，不對。看。你到一邊去。
No, no, no. Watch. Move.
拿著刀……
You hold the knife...
就這麼做。
and you just do that.
很乾淨。我試試
That's neat. Let me try.
不，不。我是個素食者，我可不想你把你的小手指頭切到菜裡去。
No, no. I'm a vegetarian. I don't want pieces of tiny little fingers in my stew.
這。你來攪拌。
Here. You stir.
你在等誰嗎？
Were you expecting someone?
嗨。
Hi.
我是羅娜。
I'm Lorna.
麥克邀請了我。
Michael invited me.
好吧，進來吧
Well, come in.
你朋友在這
Your friend's here.
嗨
Hi.
- 嗨。
- 我可以幫忙麼？
- Hi.
- Can I help?
不用，不用，沒關係。謝謝。
No. No, it's okay. Thank you.
你切到手指了。
You cut your finger.
是啊
Yeah.
這是你女朋友？
Is this your girlfriend?
嗨，我是史蒂芬。
Hi, I'm Stephen.
真好吃，寶貝。完全超出你的水平
That was delicious, babe.You outdid yourself.
為我自己的安格魯-撒克遜教徒準備的朝聖食物。
This pilgrim food for my very own WASP.
但是你得原諒我，親愛的
But you must forgive me, my darling.
我沒法做出這種果凍模具
I couldn't get myself to make one of those Jell-O molds.
這次就原諒你了
You're forgiven this time.
現在，（法語）
And now, for the pi鎗e de r閟istance.
- 我來，爸爸
- 你被逮捕了
- Let me, Dad.
- You're under arrest.
看看，你弄得肚臍那到處都是
Look at this.You got it all over your bellybutton.
看看
Look at that.
哦天哪。我老得都能把這房子弄著火。
Oh, God. I'm old enough to set the house on fire.
抱歉，我以為你媽媽叫辛西婭。
I'm sorry, I thought your mother's name was Cynthia.
過生日的時候我們都叫山姆
On birthdays, we're all Sam.
這是我們家小小的傳統……
It's a little family tradition...
是因為我1968年那次超棒的用迷幻劑的經歷
resulting from a particularly good LSD trip I took in 1968.
再來點酒？
More wine?
- 你能讓我歇會麼？
- 在歐洲，小孩子就能喝酒。
- Would you give me a break?
- In Europe, kids drink wine.
在我給「匿名酗酒者（美國一家幫助戒酒的機構）」打電話（指喝醉）之前，把給你媽媽的禮物拿來。
Get your mother her present before I call Alcoholics Anonymous.
謝謝
Thanks.
這就是我想要的
It's just what I wanted.
- 真的？
- 千真萬確
- Really?
- Absolutely.
那是什麼，蝴蝶？
What is that, a butterfly?
不是，是個鯨魚，當做禮物了
No, it's a whale of a present.
- 謝謝
- 我會彈奏它的
- Thanks.- I'll play it for you sometime.
這是羅娜的禮物
This is from Lorna.
真美
That's beautiful.
謝謝你，羅娜
Thank you, Lorna.
我的禮物，等會給你
Mine, you get later.
你保證
You bet.
沒問題
On your feet!
我來幫忙。
Let me help.
我喜歡她。
I like her.
嗯？
Yeah?
- 我也喜歡她。
- 我知道
- I like her, too.- I know.
你確定這是菲利普斯家的孩子？
You sure this is the Phillips' kid?
你在醫院沒被掉包吧，嗯？
They didn't switch you at the hospital,or anything, did they?
你知道，我不敢想像他們有多不可理喻。
You know, I can't believe how incredible they are.
你知道如果我給我媽媽一個貝殼當做生日禮物，她會怎麼做？
Do you know what my mother would do if I gave her a shell for her birthday?
沒關係吧
They're okay.
那就是你，害怕承認自己
That's you all over,afraid to commit yourself.
我以為這就是我
I thought it was just me.
和你在一起我很開心
I'm very happy with you.
我也是
I'm very happy with you, too.
沒關係，我想這樣
It's okay, I want to.
- 你沒去上廚藝課
- 你注意到了。
- You weren't in cooking.
- You noticed.
- 你去哪了？
- 我翹課了
- Where were you?- I cut.
- 為什麼？
- 我不想見你。
- Why?- I didn't want to see you.
曼菲爾德，我能和你說幾句話麼
Manfield, could I talk to you for a minute?
你沒必要這麼緊張。就算你做了錯事……
You don't have to look so anxious.If you've done something wrong...
我也不知道。我只是想知道你對大學的計劃。
I don't know about it. I just want to talk to you about your college plans.
我想休息一年，也許去歐洲旅行，聽聽音樂。
I was thinking of taking a year off, maybe traveling to Europe, listening to music.
我不能要求你做什麼，但是我覺得你應該申請大學
I can't tell you what to do, but I think you ought to make an application, anyway.
你可以推遲入學的
You can always postpone entry.
我想讓你考慮考慮申請朱利亞德（紐約一所藝術學院）
I'd like you to consider applying to Juilliard.
提前錄取
Early admission.
我看了你成績的檔案，被錄取應該沒問題
I looked at your academic records.You should have no trouble getting in.
不過，剩下的呢？
Where's the rest of it, by the way?
你的檔案裡沒有原先的學校的。
There's nothing in your file from your old school.
我們搬家的時候弄丟了。
It was lost when we moved.
找回來的時候，我想看看。
When it comes through, I'd like to see it.
同時，你看看這個。
In the meantime, you look at that.
我會樂意給你寫推薦信的。
I'd be happy to write you a letter of recommendation.
謝謝
Thank you.
看完之後還給我
Get back to me when you've looked at it.
你不和我說話
You wouldn't talk to me.
現在，起床
Now, get up.
下樓，從後門出去
Go down the stairs and out the back door.
悄悄的
Be quiet.
我就在你後面。
I'll be right behind you.
我光著腳呢
I'm barefoot.
坐下
Sit down.
我在幹嘛？
What am I doing?
我就是想和你說話。
I just wanted to talk to you.
你那天在學校不聽我講。
You wouldn't listen, the other day at school.
我那天晚上沒和你在一起，不是因為我不想。
I couldn't stay with you that night. Not because I didn't want to.
如果你想回去，對我來說沒什麼。
If you want to go back, it's fine with me.
- 你是個笨蛋。
- 不。
- You're a bully.- No.
我說了謊。
I'm a liar.
我真名不是麥克
My name isn't Michael.
是丹尼。
It's Danny.
我父母是阿瑟和安妮·波普
My parents are Arthur and Annie Pope.
1971年他們因為讓汽油彈實驗室爆炸，和聯邦調查局惹上了麻煩
They're in trouble with the FBl for blowing up a napalm lab in 1971.
有一個人差點就死了
There was a man who was almost killed.
那是個看門人，當時不該在那的
A janitor,abcwho wasn't supposed to be there.
我們在所有生日蛋糕上都寫「山姆」
We put "Sam" on the birthday cakes, on all the birthday cakes...
是因為每到一個地方，我們就換新名字
because we change our names every time we move.
從我兩歲起，就一直這樣了
I've been doing this since I was two.
我不知道別的辦法。
I don't know any other way.
我只是想告訴你我很抱歉
I just wanted to tell you that I was sorry.
我想解釋我為什麼說不了太多事
I wanted to explain why I can't talk about a lot of things.
比如大學。我不能去上大學。我不能離開他們。
Like college. I can't go to college.I can't leave them.
我還想告訴你……
And I wanted to tell you...
我為什麼不能和你在一起。
why I couldn't be with you.
不能讓你不知道。我不想對你說謊。
Not without your knowing.I didn't want to lie to you.
現在我沒權利和你說這些的
Now, I have no right in telling this to you.
對你，對他們，都很危險。
It's dangerous for you,and it's dangerous for them.
對不起，我只是控制不住自己
I'm sorry. I just couldn't stop myself.
你想做什麼都可以做，你可以告訴你爸爸。我不介意
You can do what you want to. You can tell your dad anything. I don't care.
我只是想要你知道
I just needed you to know.
我不知道我在做什麼
I don't know what I'm doing.
我愛你
And I love you.
I love you.
那我要叫你什麼？
What do I call you?
麥克。什麼都不用變
Michael. Nothing changes.
他們真的不想讓你上大學麼？
They really don't want you to go to school, huh?
我們還沒有談
We haven't talked about it.
- 我不能問他們
- 為什麼不？
- I can't ask them.- Why not?
那就意味著拆散整個家庭，我再也見不到他們。
It would mean breaking up the family,not seeing them again.
他們除了我們，什麼都沒有
They don't have anything else.
我不能相信他們會要求你耗費自己的生命去陪著他們
I can't believe that they'd want you to give up your whole life to stay with them.
和他們談。他們會理解的。
Talk to them. They'll understand.
你有很多秘密，不是麼
You have a lot of secrets, don't you?
現在你又多了一個。
Now you have another one.
去和羅娜約會了？
Been to see Lorna?
我喜歡她。
I like that one.
她很活潑
She's full of beans.
你真心喜歡她，不是麼
You really like her, don't you?
聰明的人總是最好的
The smart ones are always the best.
你和她睡了麼？
Are you sleeping with her?
- 嗯。
- 好。
- Yeah.
- Okay.
快去，睡覺去。明天還要上學。
Go ahead, hit the sack.You got school tomorrow.
你在停止專業鋼琴之後
How long have you been playing violin...
演奏了多久小提琴？
after you stopped playing seriously piano?
大概五年
About five years.
什麼時候來美國的？
When did you come to the States?
1980年
In 1980.
好的，非常感謝
All right. Thank you very much.
曼菲爾德先生，我們準備好面試你了。
Mr. Manfield. We're ready for you now.
你說你和誰學的？
Who did you say you studied with?
愛德華·菲利普斯
Edward Phillips.
- 在哪？
- 沃特福德。
- Where was this?- Waterford.
- 新澤西？
- 對
- New Jersey?- That's right.
我們好像沒有你的學校檔案
We seem not to have all your school records.
我以前的學校有，但是丟了
There was a school fire at my old school, and the records were lost.
今年我們剛搬到新澤西
We only moved to New Jersey this year.
所以你和菲利普斯先生只學了很短時間
So you've only studied with Mr. Phillipsfor a short time.
是的，太太
Yes, ma'am.
你還和誰學過？
Who else have you worked with?
很多不同的，但沒有一個這麼重要
A lot of different people.No one important.
我們經常搬家
We move a lot.
你必須給我們你的SAT成績，還有……
You'll have to supply us with SAT scores and...
我們必須要那些檔案
we'll have to have those records.
曼菲爾德先生。
Mr. Manfield.
哦，對不起
Oh, sorry.
你很有才華，你知道
You are very talented, you know.
謝謝，太太
Thank you, ma'am.
給帕特森太太的芝士比薩。
A cheese pizza for Mrs. Patterson.
帕特森太太沒訂比薩。
I don't think Mrs. Patterson ordered a pizza.
這是莫裡山68434號麼?
Is this Murray Hill 68434?
- 是
- 那有人定了比薩。
- Yes.- Someone ordered it.
稍等。
這比薩是怎麼回事？
你訂了一個。
You ordered one.
我沒有。
I didn't.
那你得付錢麼？
Will you have to pay for it?
不，我得吃
No, I'll have to eat it.
我真的不在乎。等等。你下次不能敲門麼？
I really don't care. Hold on.Could you knock next time?
- 對不起。
- 聽著，我得走了。嗯。拜拜
- I'm sorry.- Listen, I have to go. Yeah. Bye.
我在想麥克有沒有和你提到……
I was wondering if Michael had ever mentioned anything to you...
他以前的學校
about his old school.
不多。怎麼問這個？
Not much. Why?
都沒把他的檔案寄來。
They never sent his records.
然後呢？
So?
我打電話給學校，說沒有他的檔案。
I called the school.They have no record of him.
有可能是電腦刪掉了，或者什麼的。
They probably got eaten by a computer,or something.
在肯塔基州的藍山，沒有電腦的
They don't have a computer in Blue Hill, Kentucky.
你研究他做什麼？
What are you on his case for?
- 我們對他一無所知。
- 嗯，他以前是個殺人犯
- We know nothing about him.- So, he's an axe murderer.
我說，拜託！我以為他是你教過的音樂最好的學生。
I mean, come on! I thought he was the best music student you ever had.
他是，但這解釋不了他檔案丟失的問題
He is, but that doesn't explain his missing records.
如果你想知道他究竟是誰，為什麼不直接找他談？
If you want to know who he is, why don't you talk to him?
他是個人！
He's a person!
他不是電腦裡的數據
He's not a computer printout!
能不能把門關上？
Would you please close the door?
- 曼菲爾德太太？
- 是
- Mrs. Manfield?- Yes.
- 謝謝你能來
- 您好
- Thank you for coming.- How do you do?
- 要不要來點咖啡？
- 不，謝謝
- Would you like some coffee?- No, thanks.
我想和您聊聊麥克
I want to talk to you about Michael.
我不想在學校見，這樣他就不知道我們談過
I didn't want to meet at school,because he doesn't know we're talking.
但是他最近很失落也很緊張
But he's been upset lately, and nervous.
我以為可能是家裡出了點事
I thought maybe there was something at home.
沒有
No.
我知道這是私人事情。我只是覺得如果我知道的話，我能幫得上忙。
I know these things are private. I just thought maybe I could help, if I knew.
但是真的什麼事都沒有。
But there isn't anything. Really.
也許他擔心朱利亞德。
Maybe he's worried about Juilliard.
朱利亞德？
Juilliard?
您知道他的計劃？
You know about his plans?
- 是啊，當然
- 您不反對？
- Yeah, sure.- And you don't object?
不反對
No.
他們對他的面試印象深刻
They were very impressed with his audition.
他們打算一拿到他的檔案就錄取他
They're prepared to take him, just as soon as they get his records.
那時候他就得去了，是不是？
He'll have to go then, won't he?
是不是經濟困難？
Is there a financial problem?
我們可不像洛克菲勒家族那麼有錢。
We're not the Rockefellers.
他可能會擔心錢的問題
He could be worried about that.
我們還過得下去。
We always manage.
有獎學金的。他可以拿
There are scholarships. He could get one.
他很有才華
He's very talented.
我們也許不富裕，但我們關心孩子
We may not have a lot, but we care about our kids.
我當然知道您關心
I'm sure you do.
我只是想知道他有過專業的老師麼？
I was just wondering,has he ever had a serious teacher?
他是怎樣達到這個水平的？
How has he gotten this far?
我不知道
I don't know.
他在這學一點，那學一點。我們經常搬家。為什麼問這個
He's picked up a little here and there.We move around a lot. Why?
我給藍山打了電話，沒有麥克·曼菲爾德的檔案
I called Blue Hill and they have no record of Michael Manfield.
那是因為他在那註冊的時候沒有用曼菲爾德這個名字
That's because he wasn't registered there under Manfield.
你看，我以前結過婚，保羅收養了他
See, I was married before,and Paul adopted him.
但是直到今年才能合法地跟他的姓
But it took until just this year to adopt his name legally.
在藍山，他跟的是我前夫的姓
He's under my old husband's name at Blue Hill.
沒有這些檔案，他不能完成申請
He can't finish his application without those records.
我會拿到的
I'll get them.
你必須得拿，因為他們只把檔案給家長……
You'll have to, because they won't release them to anyone but a parent-
我說了，我會拿到的。行了麼？
I said, I'll get them. All right?
- 現在，我得走了
- 好的，當然
- Now, if you'll excuse me.
- Yeah, sure.
怎麼了，媽媽？
What's wrong, Mom?
沒什麼
Nothing.
我愛你
I just love you.
我要去接你爸爸
I've got to pick up your father.
喜歡麼？我把貨車賣了，買了這個。我覺得這樣更實際一點。
Do you like it? I traded the van in for it.Thought it'd be more practical.
而且，這讓他們一直猜測
Besides, it keeps them guessing.
怎麼了，山姆？
What's up, Sam?
別那麼叫我
Don't call me that.
好吧
Okay.
丹尼去申請大學了
Danny's applied to college.
在哪？
Where?
朱利亞德
Juilliard.
你怎麼知道的？
How do you know?
菲利普斯。他想讓他去
Phillips. He wants him to go.
他為什麼不離咱們家的事遠點？
Why doesn't he keep his goddamn nose out of our business?
因為他覺得他很有才華。
Because he thinks he's talented.
丹尼告訴你這些了麼？
Has Danny told you about any of this?
沒有。
No.
我們要怎麼做？
What are we going to do?
媽的
Shit.
去他媽的！
Goddamn fucking shit!
他為什麼不能去上大學？
Why can't he go?
因為如果他去了，我們就再也見不到他了。
Because we'll never see him again if he does.
為什麼不能？我們可以安排和他見面。
Why? We could arrange to meet him.
你想這樣？
Is that what you want?
在機場休息室見十分鐘，然後聯邦調查局一輩子跟在他屁股後面？
Ten minutes at an airport lounge, and the FBl all over his ass the rest of the time?
你想讓他像我父母一樣站在電話亭，洗衣房……
You want him standing in phone booths and Laundromats like my parents...
只能通過通信網絡和我們聯繫？我不想這樣。
only connecting with us through the network? I don't think so.
如果他去了，我們就再也見不到他了
If he goes,we're never going to see him again...
我不能接受。
and that is unacceptable to me.
我連想都不會想。
I never even let myself think about this.
我真傻。
I was so stupid.
我只想讓我們在一起
All I wanted was that we would be together.
我應該把丹尼扔給我媽媽的
We should have left Danny with my mother.
- 我們都不該有哈利
- 閉嘴。
- We never should have had Harry.- Stop it.
我不能這樣，阿瑟。看看我們對孩子都做了些什麼。
I can't, Arthur.Look what we're doing to these kids.
他們一輩子都像罪犯一樣在逃亡。
They've been running their whole lives like criminals.
他們什麼都沒做！
And they didn't do anything!
這不公平
It isn't fair.
我知道這他媽的不公平。
I know it isn't goddamned fair.
他們經過了一些衝擊，但是你這樣逼自己於事無補
They've taken some bumps, but it's not going to help anything to beat yourself up.
看看他們，看在上帝的份上。
Look at them, for God's sake.
看看這些孩子。他們多麼優秀
Look at those kids. They're magnificent.
他們很美
They're beautiful.
很聰明很體貼
And bright. Caring.
我們能做得多壞呢？
How badly could we have done?
我們應該自首
We should turn ourselves in.
然後接下來15年都呆在監獄裡……
So we can sit in prison for the next 15 years...
從鐵窗裡看我們的孩子們？
and look at the kids through bars?
每次還只能看一個小時
You can only get through this one day, one hour at a time.
我就準備這麼做。
That's what I'm doing.
丹尼已經長大了。
And Danny's all grown up.
我們該放他走了
We have to let him go.
這顆牙疼死我了
This tooth is killing me.
我覺得補的東西掉了。該去看看喬納。
I think I lost a filling. Better go see Jonah.
我會坐公交車。
I'll take a bus.
- 你去市內的時候我總是擔心
- 為什麼？
- I always worry when you go into the city.- Why?
因為在那他們誰都能看見
Because that's where they get everyone.
很安靜。
It's been quiet.
有時候太安靜了
Sometimes it gets too quiet.
你還記得孩子小時候你常說的話麼？
Remember what you used to say when the kids were small?
「別著急，除非你什麼都聽不見了。」
"Don't worry unless you don't hear anything. "
小心點，好不好？
Be careful, all right?
我什麼都沒看見。X光片裡也什麼都沒有。
I don't see anything. And there's nothing on the x-ray.
我沒在抱怨。
I'm not complaining.
還需要什麼嗎？
You need anything else?
不，謝謝。我們很好。我在為一個全科醫生工作。
No, thanks. We're okay. I'm working for a GP.
現金可以嗎？
How about cash?
可以
Okay.
如果你提前告訴我，我可以安排更多的
If you'd give me some notice, I could arrange to have more.
不。很好了。謝謝
No. This is great. Thanks.
- 你總是讓我覺得這麼愧疚。
- 為什麼？
- You always make me feel so guilty. - Why?
這就是你的生活方式。
You're living it.
是啊，我猜我是。
Yeah, I guess I am.
喬納，我需要你幫我打個電話
Jonah, I need youabcto make a phone call for me.
當然可以
Of course.
夫人？
Madame?
嗨，爸爸
Hi, Dad.
我讓喬納做的這個
I asked Jonah to set this up.
如果你想，可以叫警察
You can call the cops if you want to.
對不起。
I'm sorry.
這對我也很難
This is hard for me, too.
- 夫人要點什麼飲料？
- 不，謝謝
- Will madame have a drink?- No, thank you.
我想知道14年不見你的孩子
I wonder if you'll ever know what it's like...
是什麼感覺
not to see your child for 14 years.
連他是死是活都不知道
Not knowing whether she's living or dead.
不知道這孩子是不是
Not knowing whether that child...
要對別人的死亡或者傷殘負責
is responsible for the death and mutilation of other human beings.
要不要讓你自己
Whether to hold yourself responsible...
為那死亡或傷殘負責任
for that death and mutilation...
因為扣動扳機，引爆炸彈的是你的孩子
because it is your child who is pulling the triggers, setting the bombs.
我沒殺任何人
I didn't kill anybody.
我不是來為自己辯護或是談政治的
I didn't come here to defend myself or to talk politics.
如果你不相信我當時那麼做是出於良心要結束戰爭
If you don't believe by now that what I did was an act of conscience to stop the war...
那我說什麼你都不會明白
then there's nothing I can say to you that's going to make you understand.
一個人失明，還殘疾了
A man was blinded and paralyzed.
他本不該在那的。
He wasn't supposed to be there.
你不覺得，有些時候
Don't you think there have been times...
我寧願讓自己失明，讓自己殘疾，來挽回這一切麼？
that I would have blinded and paralyzed myself to take that back?
那都是阿瑟的影響。
It's all Arthur's influence.
不，爸爸，不是
No, Dad, it isn't.
是我的主意。
It was my idea.
我活在我自己的選擇帶來的後果中
I'm living with the consequences of my own choice.
- 我不信。
- 那是你的問題
- I don't believe it.- Well, that's your problem.
你媽媽和我……
Your mother and me...
你為我們考慮過麼？
Do you think about us?
- 你非得這麼問麼
- 對。
- Do you really have to ask that?- Yes.
上一次我記得你對我說
The last thing I remember you saying to me...
我是個帝國主義的蠢豬
was that I was an imperialist pig...
一個人為了戰爭，貧窮和種族主義承擔責任
personally responsible for the war, the spread of poverty, racism.
- 我還年輕
- 是
- I was young.- Yes.
你還年輕
You were young.
有才華
And talented.
美麗
And beautiful.
那麼充滿了愛
And so full of love.
上帝啊，安妮。你為什麼把它們都拋棄了？
My God, Annie.Why did you throw it all away?
你媽媽很想你。還有丹尼
Your mother misses you terribly. And Danny.
你會收留他麼，爸爸
Will you take him, Dad?
他想學音樂
He wants to study music.
他很好
He's good.
他們想讓他去朱利亞德
They want him at Juilliard.
就像他們當時想讓你一樣
Just like they wanted you.
你還有那個用來練習的板？
Do you still have that practice board?
一直到現在。丹尼就是在那上面學會彈琴。
So far. Danny learned to play piano on it.
你教他的？
So you taught him?
不覺得這有點諷刺麼？
There's some irony in this, don't you think?
你現在在這
Here you are...
求我把丹尼帶到
asking me to take Danny...
你曾經唯恐避之不及的人生裡
into a life that you ran from like a shot out of hell.
他真的想要麼？
Is this what he wants?
我覺得是
I think so.
他沒告訴我就自己去了面試
He got himself an audition without telling me.
他會需要錢和照顧他的人
He'll need money, and people to care for him.
你不覺得你要的太多了麼？
Don't you think this is too much to ask?
我幾乎不認識這男孩
I hardly know the boy.
如果我們收留了他
If we take him...
那我們去哪都會有聯邦調查局的人跟著
there'd be FBl agents following us everywhere we go.
你就再也見不到他
You'd never be able to see him.
我們太老了，不能這麼做了
We're too old for this.
嗯，我覺得我要的太多了
Yeah, I think it's too much to ask.
我還有一個兒子
I have another son.
他十歲。叫哈利。
He's 10. Harry.
我在新聞上聽說了
I heard about it on the news.
我打算
I plan to turn myself in...
在他再也不需要我的時候就去自首，在他足夠大的時候
when he doesn't need me anymore.When he's old enough.
阿瑟呢？
And Arthur?
我不能為他說話
I can't speak for him.
請你考慮考慮
Please think about this.
我該走了
I should go.
安妮。
Annie.
他可以來我們家
He can come to us.
請您告訴媽媽，我愛她
Please, tell Mom that I love her.
我經常想你倆
And I've thought about you both so often.
我把你叫出來。
I've called out to you.
對不起我給你們帶來這麼多痛苦
I'm sorry that I've caused you so much pain.
我猜我要知道這是什麼感覺了
I guess I'm about to see what it feels like.
我愛你，爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我去見了我父親
I saw my father.
你什麼？
You what?
我見了唐納德
I saw Donald.
你就那麼走進他辦公室坐在他桌邊？
You just walked into his office and sat down at his desk?
沒有
No.
我在「小鍋」和他吃了午飯
I had lunch with him at La Petite Marmite.
幹什麼？
What for?
想看看他要不要收留丹尼.
To see if he'd take Danny.
收留丹尼？
Take Danny?
這樣他就可以上大學了
So he can go to college.
你開玩笑吧
You're kidding.
他說他會的
He said he would.
他說他會？
He said he would?
你知不知道會發生什麼？
You know what could have happened?
菲利普斯要你這麼做的？
Did Phillips put you up to this?
沒人要求我這麼做
Nobody put me up to this.
和菲利普斯無關。這是為了丹尼。
It's not about Phillips. It's about Danny.
他想去。他申請了，去了面試。
He wants to go. He applied.He went to an audition.
- 他他媽的去哪了？
- 朱利亞德
- He went fucking where?- Juilliard.
我不相信我的耳朵。
I don't believe my ears.
就給他一次機會吧。
Just give him a chance.
我要給黛博拉打電話，看看她能不能假造些檔案
I'm going to call Deborah and see if she can make him up some records.
為什麼？
Why?
因為菲力普斯給我填在申請表上的學校打了電話Because Phillips called the school I put on the registration form...
然後他們告訴他沒有叫麥克·曼菲爾德的人
and they told him there was no Michael Manfield.
會沒事的。
It's going to be okay.
他可以及時做好檔案的。阿瑟！
He can get records made up in time. Artie!
我們要搬了，孩子們
We're moving base camp, kids.
再呆幾天，我們就走。
We have a few days, and we're gone.
把蹤跡都銷毀掉。
Cover your tracks.
聽見沒？
You hear me?
你有想告訴我的事麼？
You have anything you want to tell me?
沒有。
No.
好。
Good.
我爸爸想要搬走。
My father wants to move on.
為什麼？
Why?
他有眼見。
He gets a sense.
就那樣？
Just like that?
就那樣。
Just like that.
什麼時候？
When?
隨時。
Anytime.
你就那麼消失了？
You'll just disappear?
那我們怎麼辦？
What about us?
- 他們需要我。
- 我需要你！
- They need me.- I need you!
你沒和他們談？
You didn't talk to them?
你不能一直逃離你沒有責任的事
You can't keep running from something you had nothing to do with.
你應該有你自己的機會
You deserve your own chance.
- 我想和你談談
- 沒什麼可談的
- I want to talk to you.- There's nothing to talk about.
菲利普斯知道的太多了
Phillips knows too much.
你在讓你的情感影響你的判斷。
You were letting your feelings affect your judgment.
而且，這就是上學
Besides, it's academic.
沒人會說的
Nobody will talk.
你不知道。
You don't know that.
他們能抓的都會抓。
They're going to try to pick up everyone they can now.
我們在這的日子到頭了。
We're finished here.
- 我們可以慢慢收手的，不是麼？
- 我們必須走了
- We can close up shop slowly, can't we?- We'll have to.
不然就會引起注意
Otherwise we'll attract attention.
大家都去上班和上學，等接下來的通知
Everybody goes to work and school until further notice.
如果有問題我們就在80號公路附近的野餐區見面
If there's a problem,will meet at the picnic area near Route 80.
還沒有理由覺得他們在追捕我們，所以冷靜
There's no reason to think they're onto us yet, so stay calm.
- 爸爸，我能和你說一會話麼？
- 現在不行。
- Dad, can I talk to you a minute?- Not now.
我想留下。
I was thinking about staying.
- 你不得去上課麼？
- 還有半個小時
- Don't you have school?- In half an hour.
我想留下。
I want to stay.
留下？
Stay?
你覺得現在是討論這個問題的時候麼
Do you think this is a good time to discuss this?
我們現在不能說。我們遇到麻煩了。
We can't talk now. We're in trouble here.
我告訴你了！
I taught you!
我告訴你了！我們不能打破我們之間的聯繫
I taught you! We cannot break rank.
一個集體的能力是由它最弱的一環決定的
A unit is only as good as its weakest link.
我們是一個集體！
We're a unit!
這些都是我教你的，不記得了麼？
I taught you all of this,don't you remember that?
我不想聽你
I don't want to hear you talking about this...
在你媽媽或者你弟弟面前說這些，聽見沒有？
in front of your mother or your brother, do you hear me?
我說，聽見沒有？
I said, do you hear me?
這回說完了沒？
Are we finished talking about this now?
泰勒女士
Mrs. Taylor.
把所有東西都拿出來，穿上袍子就行
Just remove everything and put on the gown.
幾分鐘內就可以見醫生了
The doctor will see you in a few minutes.
好的。我馬上就回來給你稱體重
All right. I'll be right back to weigh you.
能幫我拉拉鏈麼，親愛的？
Could you help me with this zipper, dear?
你知道昨晚伊利莎白·鮑威爾怎麼了麼？
Did you hear what happened to Elizabeth Powell last night?
不知道
No, I didn't.
聯邦調查局找她了
The FBl came to see her.
搶銀行，還殺死了警察的那次
The car that was used in that bank robbery...
他們用的車
where they killed those policemen...
是用她的信用卡租的
it was rented with her credit card.
你相信麼？
Can you believe it?
他們怎麼能拿到她的卡？她自己都從來不用。
How could they have got hold of her card? She never even uses it herself.
這就是為什麼她沒注意到卡不見了
That's how come she didn't notice it was gone.
那些人是一幫惡棍，泰勒女士
Those people are crooks, Mrs. Taylor.
他們很有可能就是從通訊錄裡查出她的電話
They probably just took her name out of the phone book...
然後假造了一張卡。
and made up a false card.
能想像這多背運麼？
Can you imagine the bad luck?
請找保羅·曼菲爾德先生。我是他妻子。
Paul Manfield, please. His wife.
我們很著急。
We're in a hurry.
格斯從我一個病人那偷了信用卡。他用它來租車。
Gus took plastic from one of my patients.He used it to rent the car.
真的？我要去抽根煙
Frankie? I'm going out for a smoke.
- 我們著急麼，媽媽？
- 嗯。我們得找到丹尼。
- Are we in a hurry, Mom?- Yeah. We have to get Danny.
希望你丈夫還好。
I hope your husband is all right.
好了，走吧
Okay, let's go.
- 媽媽，我在那見你
- 我們時間不多。
- Mom, I'll meet you there.- We don't have much time.
塞林格在《麥田里的守望者》中用意象……
Salinger uses imagery in Catcher in the Rye to-
- 抱歉。
- 怎麼？
- Excuse me.- Yes?
麥奎爾先生要見羅娜·菲利普斯
Mr. McGuire would like to see Lorna Phillips.
- 他寫假條了麼？
- 沒有，女士。
- Did he send a note?- No, ma'am.
菲利普斯小姐？
Ms. Phillips?
我們要走了。
We're leaving.
你沒和他們談？
You didn't ask them?
我談了。
I did.
阿瑟崩潰了。
Artie fell apart.
他根本不講理。
He didn't even make any sense.
沒有我們他活不下去。
Without us, he can't keep it going.
他需要我們支撐著他。
He needs us to hold him up.
所有家庭都會拆散的。
All families break up.
為什麼要把別人的人生當做自己的負擔？
Why do you have to carry the burden of someone else's life?
他是我父親
He's my father.
我愛你。
I love you.
但是我要離開了。
But I have to go.
我不知道怎麼道別。
I don't know how to say goodbye.
那就不要。
Well, don't.
- 他在哪？
- 他會來這。
- Where is he? - He'll be here.
他去和她女朋友道別了
He went to say goodbye to his girlfriend.
他比這知道得多
He knows better than this.
這裡是鮑勃·斯通，帶來Z-90新聞時間
This is Bob Stone, with a Z-90 newsbreak.
新澤西警方昨天下午報告了
New Jersey police have reported the death of Liberation Army member Gus Winant...
在搶劫銀行後一直在逃的自由軍成員格斯·維納特的死亡
at large after the bank robbery yesterday afternoon.
他在沃特福德附近偷了輛車並試圖逃逸，
He was shot resisting arrest near Waterford...
因拒捕而被槍擊。
where he had stolen a car,and was attempting to flee.
五點帶來更多，現在回到球賽。
More at 5:00.We return you now to the ball game.
把自行車從後面拿出來。
Get the bike out of the back.
騎上。
Now get on it.
你在說什麼，爸爸……
What are you talking about, Dad-
騎上車。你現在靠自己了，孩子
Get on the bike. You're on your own, kid.
我想讓你去朱利亞德
I want you to go to Juilliard.
但是爸爸，我想和你走
But, Dad, I want to go with you.
我們會再見的。你放心。
We'll see you again. You can be sure.
你媽媽和你外公都安排好了。
Your mother has arranged things with your grandfather.
給他打電話。
Call him.
你在這也有了些朋友了。
And I think you have some friends around here.
我愛你，寶貝兒
I love you, baby.
我們都愛你。
We all love you.
現在，去闖自己的人生吧
Now, go out there and make a difference.
你和我媽媽試過了。
Your mother and I tried.
不要讓任何人懷疑你。
Don't let anyone tell you any different.
再見，丹尼！
Goodbye, Danny!
English